本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
That which goes does not go.
That which comes does not come.
行く者は行かず　来る者は来ない
The moon is the sun.
月は太陽　小鳥は魚
The birds are the fish.
Magic begins with visualization.
魔法はイメージから始まる
Destroy the order of the
world within yourself,
自らの中にある世界の秩序を破壊し
while visualizing your destruction
of the world's order.
同時に世界の秩序を破壊するイメージだ
The living are the dead.
生者は骸　鋼鉄はおもろ
Steel becomes brittle.
Reality becomes a dream.
All fantasy becomes reality.
現は夢にして　幻想はすべての現になり
Using your right to defy the creator,
創造主に逆らう権利の行使
and deviating from universal law...
世界の公理からの逸脱
それを人は魔法と言うんだ
This, we call "magic."
That which is, is not.
ある物はなく　なき物はあり
This which is not, is.
Creation will be rendered false.
万物を虚偽と定義して
I shall now undergo Magical Deliberation.
これより魔術審議を執り行う
Invert a cup, and water spills out.
逆さにしたコップから水が落ちる
It is this logic that we defy.
その理に逆らう　それが魔法の第一歩　魔術審議の始まり
This is the first step toward magic...
The start of Magical Deliberation.
And if that deliberation is continued...
そして審議が進めば…
すげえ
Incredible...
Am I still unable to become a monster?
まだか？　「怪物」になれるのは
まだまだだ
You have a long way ahead.
What Master Ganbanzel desires
ガンバルゼル様が望むのは　ハミュッツ＝メセタだ
is Hamyuts Meseta.
I'm starving.
飯　飯
Oh, hey. I'm back.
おっ　クモラ　帰ったぞ
Welcome back.
お疲れ様
Good work today.
お疲れ様なのです
Welcome back.
お疲れ様
Yes... It's fun.
あー　楽しいさ　楽しければ笑える
Have fun, and you'll smile.
It's so pretty!
あーは　きれい
It was lying on the beach.
砂浜に落ちていったんだ
Ronkeny found it.
ロンケニーが見つけたんだよ
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
Men read Books,
人が「本」を読み　人が人の中で息を吹き返す
and men return to life inside them.
How fascinating...
面白いものです
止まる者　愚かなりし
The one who stops is foolish
はらりひらり指に触れた黒い翼の　一片
A piece of black wing gently touches fingers
诸
神字幕组
君が一つの　物語なら
If you were a story
まだいくらでも　掛け替えられる
You could still rewrite it all you want
血のインクは乾かない
The ink of blood doesn't dry up
誰も知らない　本との僕ら
No one knows the real us
荒れた世界　枯れるのは
What changes the chaotic world
追い求めたのは　ちっぽけな幸福なんかじゃない
What we pursued isn't
Small happiness
戦え　轟く　音を合図に
Fight with a rumbling heartbeat as a sign
意のまま　進めば
What awaits you is infinite if you
move forward as you wish
行く先　果てない
抗え　のたうち
Fight off no matter how many
times you get defeated
幾度と　汚れと
Engrave your dream onto the scar you bear
膝を纏った傷跡に夢を
埋もれそうな今日の記憶繋げるために　明日へ
In order to connect today's memory that's
on the verge of being buried to tomorrow
Episode 7
A Smile, a Mask, and a Man with a Death Wish
第7话 笑容
与
面具
和
求死的男人
What are you talking about, Kayas?
どういうことだよ　カヤス
Sure, the fireballs that Ronkeny
blows are powerful,
うん　確かにロンケニーの吐く火の玉は威力がある
but what's the use if he can't hit his target?
でも　当たらなきゃ意味がないと思うが
Besides, he can only fire them
a short distance now.
それに　射程距離もまだまだだ
Personally, I don't care how much
killing power you've got,
いくら相手を殺す力があっても
it isn't magic if you can't really use it.
使えなければ魔法として成立してないと思う
You might be right.
そう…かな
What do you think, Enlike?
エリケンはどう思う？
Leave him alone.
止せよ
この中で一番魔術審議が進んでいるのはエリケンだろう
But his Magical Deliberation is further
along than the rest of us.
I have no opinion on it.
どうとも思わない
Oh, he spoke.
あっ　喋った
殺しの申し子でも話しかけられれば喋るんだな
I guess even a born killer,
when spoken to, will speak.
ササリ
Sassali!
Whatever...
けっ！
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます…
Ronkeny.
ロンケニー
あ　エリケン
Enlike...
Tonight. You and me.
今夜　俺とお前だ
嘘だろう
No way...
So we're going to practice
through actual combat, huh?
実戦の訓練…なんだよね
Yes.
そうだ
And we're fighting to the death, huh?
どちらかが倒れるまで　続けるんだよね
Yes.
そうだ
Why must we do this?
どうしてこんなことしなきゃいけないの？
To become a monster.
「怪物」になるためだ
I don't want to be some stupid monster...
俺は「怪物」になんかなりたくない　皆と一緒にいたい
I want to stay with everyone.
That's impossible.
それは無理だ
どうして？
Why?!
We're only here so we can become monsters.
俺たちは「怪物」になるためにここにいるからだ
So, you came.
来ていたか？
Yes.
あ
Then let the sparring commence.
では実戦訓練を行う
これを…
Take this!
いらない
I don't want it.
It's not for you. I want you
to give it to Qumola.
君じゃない　クモラに渡してほしいんだ
Qumola?
クモラ？
Please!
お願い
では　訓練始め
Without further ado, fight!
Enlike Bishile, wielding thunder.
エリケン＝ビスハイル　雷を操る
Ronkeny Loinemoney, wielding fire.
ロンケニー＝ロイマイン　炎を操る
エリケン＝ビスハイル　今よりも強い雷を操る
Enlike Bishile, wielding even
more powerful thunder.
Ronkeny Loinemoney, wielding fire
with even greater precision.
ロンケニー＝ロイマイン　今より精密に炎を操る
エリケン＝ビスハイル　今よりも強く精密に雷を操る
Enlike Bishile, wielding even more powerful
thunder with still greater precision.
Ronkeny Loinemoney, wielding even larger,
more powerful fire with still greater precision!
ロンケニー＝ロイマイン　今より精密で強く大きな炎を
あ、あのう　ザトウさん
Hey!
Zatoh!
Zatoh Rondohoon!
ザトウ＝ロンドホーンさん
返事をしてください
Please say something!
息を…止め　心臓に達している
He isn't breathing...
It went through to his heart.
This can't be...
そんな
Where is Hamyuts Meseta?
ハミュッツ＝メセタは？
What?
は？
Where is Hamyuts... The Armed Librarian...
ハミュッツ　どこだ？　武装司書
い、生きてる
Y-You're alive?
連れて…来い　ハミュッツを
Bring Hamyuts here...
Th-This isn't the time for that!
そ、そんな　それより…
嘘
No way.
Suicide? Were you trying to commit suicide?
自殺？　自殺しようとしていたんですか？
Yes.
そうだ
Why?
どうしてですか？
なにか辛いことでもあったんですか？
Are you going through a tough time?
L-Listen!
とにかく…
まさか　自殺はよくないからやめろというんじゃないだろうな
You aren't going to preach to me that
suicide is bad, and I shouldn't do it, are you?
Suicide is bad, and you shouldn't do it.
自殺はよくないから　やめたほうがいいと思います
あっ　てば　盗みくらいで自殺しないでください
A-Anyway, don't kill yourself just
because you stole something!
うん？
ちゃんと自首すればそんなに罪は重くないと思います
I think they'll be pretty lenient
if you turn yourself in.
I stole something?
盗み？
I know you stole Luimon Muhatonn's Book,
ルイモン＝マハトンさんの「本」を盗んだんですよね
Zatoh Rondohoon.
ザトウ＝ロンドホーンさん
私　その「本」を探しにこの街に来たんです
I came to this town in search of that book.
あっ　返してくれるんですか？
You're going to give it to me?
返してほしければ　俺を殺せ
If you want it from me, kill me.
殺す？
Kill you?
Do it yourself or call another to do it.
お前でもいい　ほかの者を呼んでもいい
Kill me.
俺を殺せ
What have I been saying?
だから言ってるじゃないですか
「本」を盗むのは確かによくないことですけど
Sure, stealing a book is a sin,
but it's not worth dying for!
死ぬほどのことじゃ…
You're wrong!
違う！
Huh?
俺は殺し続けて来たんだ
I'm a killer.
もうこれ以上ないほどに　取り返しがつかないほどに
I've killed more than I can count.
I can never atone for my sins.
Even so...
それでも　それでも死んじゃだめです
Even so, you must not die.
なぜ？
Why not?
Because I'm against it.
私が　いやだからです
俺を殺さない限り　「本」は返さない
You're not getting the Book
back without killing me.
Noloty, do you copy?
ノロティ　聞こえる？
Milepoc?
ミレボッくさん？
手短にお願い　ルイモンさんの「本」は？
I don't have a lot of time.
Did you find Luimon's Book?
Yes. I found a Book that appears to be his.
はい　それらしき「本」を見つけました
Great work. Did you recover it?
よくやったのね　回収したが？
No. I found the person I believe
to have stolen it, but he's...
いいえ　犯人と思われる人が会ったんですが
なんかその人…
Kill him.
殺しなさい
Huh? But...
はぁ？でも…
You'll understand why later.
詳しいことは後からでも分かるわ
Or rather, the longer you procrastinate,
the more danger we'll be in.
むしろ　長引かせることで余計な危険が増す
But!
でも…
That danger may spread
all the way to Bantorra!
バントーラに危険が及ぶかもしれない
No, I'm against it.
それでもいやです
I will bring the Book back. Goodbye.
「本」は必ず持って帰ります
じゃ　これで
Noloty, wait!
ノロティ　待ちなさい
どうして皆　殺すとか死ぬとか　そんなことばかり
How come all anyone thinks
of is death and killing?
Long ago, that man killed another
man and read his Book.
彼はね　かつて一人の人を殺し　その「本」を読んだの
He then began to wish for death.
そして　死ぬことを望むようになった
Save that man, Zatoh.
彼を　ザトウ君を助けなさい
When he's truly in peril, save him.
彼が心底困った時に彼を助けてあげなさい
捜索するのがルイモンさんの「本」なら
I thought she'd shed some of her naïveté,
given that it's Luimon's book she's after...
少しは甘さも消えるかと思ったけど
Forget that. What are you gonna
do about this love letter?
それよりどうする？　このラブレター
"The one who is with Noloty is the
monster who attacked the Library..."
ノロティと一緒にいるのが図書館を襲った「怪物」よ
後よろしくねぇ
"Please look after things
for me from now on."
I've no doubt. This is the Acting
Director's handwriting.
この字　代行に間違いない
The Acting Director, Noloty, whoever...
まったく　代行といい　ノロティといい
Why do all women act so stupid?
女ってのはどうしてこうなるんじゃ？
ああ　すまん　ついミレボッくが女だということ忘れとた
Oh, sorry! I just forgot that you're
a woman, too, Milepoc!
ほっとくわけにはいきません　誰かを派遣するしかないでしょう
Well, I can't leave things as they are.
I'll have to dispatch someone.
You're up, Minth.
仕事だぞ　ミンス
わし？
Me?
I came to this town in
search of that Book.
私　その「本」を探しにこの街に来たんです
銃を使え　ノロティ
Draw your gun, Noloty!
No! I will not use a gun!
いやです　銃は使いません
Why not?
どうして？
殺せすぎるからです
It's too easy to kill with them!
殺したくなくても　殺してしまうからです
You end up killing, even when
you don't intend to!
You're such a sweet girl.
君は優しい子だねえ
しかし僕たちの仕事は詰まる所　死の管理だ
However, it is our job to oversee death.
You may be reprimanded for
choosing not to kill,
殺さない事で責められることはあっても
but you will never be praised.
誉められることはない
責められてもかまいません
I don't care if they reprimand me.
私は殺さずに　世界を守ってみせます
I will protect the world, without killing!
ここまで強く
She's that strong...
早くしないと
I have to hurry...
They must be killed!
こいつを殺さないと
I must admit, I'm surprised.
意外と呆気ないのね
H-Hamyuts Meseta?!
あっ　ハミュッツ＝メセタ
羨ましいわね　幸せそうな
I'm jealous. You look so happy...
You aren't powerful enough to even
approach Hamyuts. However...
お前の力はハミュッツには遠く及ばない
だが　ガンバルゼル様について行けば
If you follow Master Ganbanzel,
a day will come when you'll be able to kill her.
いつか必ず殺せる日が来る
This isn't a smile.
笑顔じゃない
あ？
Huh?
This...
これは…笑顔じゃない
isn't a smile.
お疲れ様なのです
Welcome back.
きれい
It's beautiful.
You got this from Ronkeny, didn't you?
ロンケニーさんですね
How can you tell?
どうして分かる？
He said he'd bring me another...
また　拾ってくるって言ってたから
Why don't you smile?
どうして　笑わない？
Why...
don't you smile?
A back alley?
裏通り？
Yes, according to police intel.
ええ　保安官の情報では
Though, we don't know for
sure if he's the monster.
ただ　その男が本物の「怪物」かどうか…
Well, I have an idea.
まっ　一応手は考えてある
But I'm not sure if it'll work.
うまくいくか分からんが
Play nice with my monster,
Armed Librarians.
わしの「怪物」をよろしく頼むぞ　武装司書
Those guys...
お客さん来ませんね
The customers aren't lining up today, huh?
Why are you here?
なぜ…ここにいる？
Because I want to help you.
ザトウさんを助けたいからです
Then kill me.
なら　俺を殺せ
それは助けることにはなりません
That wouldn't be helping you!
That's the only way to help me!
殺す以外に方法はない
There's another way.
I just haven't figured it out yet.
ありますよ
まだ分からないですけど
Why are you smiling?
なぜ　笑う？
Huh? That's a good question...
なんでですかなぁ
多分　安心しているんだと思います
It's probably because my mind's at ease...
すくなくとも　こうしている間は
Because you haven't attempted suicide again
during the time we've spent together.
ザトウさん　自殺しようとしないですから
Someone might punch me to death.
誰かに　殴り殺されるかもしれない
There isn't anyone in this town
who can knock you out.
この街にザトウさんを倒せる人はいません
I mean, I don't like watching
you get punched,
もちろん　殴られているのを見るのは苦手ですけど
but it's better than you being
stabbed with a knife!
ナイフでさされるよりはましですから
なぜ笑った？
Why did you smile?
あ？
Why did you hold my hand?
なぜ俺の手を握った？
あれは…言ったじゃないですか
That was... I already told you!
守ってくれると思ったからです　世界を一緒に
Because you're going to protect
the world with me.
"Come and punch me, for a fee
of 100 kiluwes per minute."
参加料一分百キロエ　殴り倒せたら一万キロエ
"Beat me and win 10,000 kiluwes."
Is that him?
この男か？
What an awesome mask!
すごい仮面　大道芸の人ですかね？
You must be a street performer, huh?
あっ　痛い
Ow! Ow!
千キロエだ　十分間殴らせてもらうぞ
Here's a thousand kiluwes.
I'm gonna punch you for ten minutes.
No way! It's one minute at a time!
そんな　１回１分じゃ…
It's okay.
かまわん
え？
Huh?
行くぜ
Here I come!
相は愚　思考は虚無　望みは贖罪？
His dominant trait is stupidity.
His thoughts are empty.
And he wishes for atonement?
He's nothing like the monster.
この前の「怪物」とは似てもにつかん
ただ　この仮面に反応をした
However, he did react to my mask!
So why?!
ザトウさん
Zatoh!
That man is incredibly strong.
この人凄く強い　今までの人とは全然違う
He's on a different level
from the others.
And yet, Zatoh is taking all of his blows!
なのにザトウさん　ちゃんとまともに受けている
He couldn't be!
まさか…
Hey!
ちょっと…
偽者に殺される　この俺に相応しい
To be killed by an imposter...
How fitting...
Imposter?
偽者？
Stop! That's against the rules!
ダメです　ルール違反です
You paid to punch him.
You can't do anything else!
殴る屋ですから　殴る以外は反則です
来い　俺を殺せ
Come on. Kill me...
Nothing has changed within him.
何ひとつ変わらん　魂の中にあの「怪物」の手掛かりはない
There's no trace of the monster
within his soul.
Still!
じゃ…
Please stop!
やめてください
どけ
Move.
いやです
No.
どけ
Move!
どうして　どうして死ななきゃいけないんですか？
Why?
Why do you have to die?
俺はかつてたくさんの人を殺した
I killed countless people in the past.
The fact that I'm alive is an
affront to their very souls.
俺が生きるということは
俺が殺してきた人の命を冒瀆するということだ
And your death will make amends for that?
死ぬことで償えるんですか？
There's no other way!
ほかに方法がない
Everyone dies!
誰だって死ぬんです　そんなことで償いになるんですか？
That won't make up for a damned thing!
You have nothing you wish
to do before you die?!
何もないんですか？
死ぬ前にしたいこと　何もないんですか？
Nothing at all?!
何かあるでしょう
There must be something!
ひとつくらい　何かあるでしょう
At least one thing, right?!
Zatoh!
ザトウさん
死ぬ前に…笑いたい
I want to smile before I die...
笑いたい
I want to smile.
Zatoh...
ザトウさん
Zatoh!
Ow-ow...
いたた…
Minth!
ミンスさん
今頃気づいたんか？
Now you figure it out?
What on Earth are you doing here?
どうしてこんなところに？
We got word that the monster was here.
「怪物」がここにいると情報があったんじゃ
「怪物」？
Monster?
The gold-masked monster
that attacked Bantorra.
バントーラを襲った黄金の仮面を被った「怪物」じゃ
That lightning attack was unmistakable.
あの雷撃　間違いない
そんな　でもザトウさんは…
No way. Zatoh's just...
あ　確かに不同人
I agree. It doesn't make sense.
聖浄眼で見る限り　明らかに別人
Looking at him with my Sacred Eyes,
he's a completely different person.
The monster who attacked Bantorra
has a dominant trait of misfortune,
バントーラを襲ったのは相は凶　思考は私利　望みは混沌
his thoughts are of himself,
and he wishes for chaos.
贖罪など少しも考えてなかった
He's never thought of atonement in his life!
It was my first time seeing him too,
わしも見るのは初めてじゃが
but he's probably...
あれは恐らく…
I...
俺は…　俺は…
Excellent, excellent.
順調　順調
Looks like it's almost time...
そろそろかな
本当の「怪物」っ子ちゃんの誕生
For the real monster to be born.
Zatoh!
ザトウさん
Stay away, Noloty...
ノロティ　来るな
You can smile.
笑えますよ
楽しいことがいっぱいあれば　笑うなんて簡単です
It's easy to smile if you surround
yourself with fun things!
Fun things?
楽しいこと？
はい　楽しいことがいっぱいあれば
Yes!
If you surround yourself with fun things,
you'll be able to want to go on living.
生きていたいって思えます
ふん　そうか
Is that so?
So please... Don't die!
だから　死なないでください
Zatoh?
ザトウさん？
Get the hell away from here, Noloty!
離れるんじゃう　ノロティ
それじゃ　生きるためにたっぷり楽しませてもらおうか
Then I suppose, in the name of living,
I'll have to enjoy all sorts of fun.
Fun! Fun! Murder!
楽しい　楽しい　人殺しを
Lost the light
Before closing the sun
If it's a sparkling storm
Jump in before it tempts
The end comes to everyone one day
When the day comes
Aim for the future that begins to move
Even if it's already been written
Search and even acquire the
meaning of getting hurt
In order to be myself
A Pond,
浜辺の貝殻
A seashell...
A Pond, Comrades,
If you put your ear to it, you can
hear the melodies of the past:
耳を当てれば過去も見える
If you put your ear to it, you can
hear the melodies of the past:
death throes of fallen comrades,
仲間たちの断滅も
沼泽与同伴和海边的贝壳
A Pond, Comrades, and a Seashell
death throes of fallen comrades,
insignificant chatter,
そして他愛無いお喋り　笑い声
and laughter.